Vasanth Krishnamoorthy

San Francisco Bay Area | vasanth.kmy@gmail.com | 541.602.7491 | vasanthk.com

OVERVIEW

Leader in tech with 13 yrs of experience working at scale in companies ranging from a startup to Fortune 1. I love people / technology and enjoy scaling them to their peak performance. I have led full stack teams of 4 to 40 devs with great success.

SKILLS

LEADERSHIP

SPECIALTIES:

Technical Leadership • Org Strategy • People Management • Hiring • SDLC Operational Excellence • Project Management • Agile • Public Speaking Communication & Collaboration

TECHNOLOGY

SPECIALTIES:

JavaScript • HTML • CSS • React • Web Performance • Distributed Systems • React Native • Redux • TypeScript • GraphQL • Next.js • Node.js • Webpack • Babel • Git

Familiar with:

Python • PHP • C • Java • XSLT • SEO Swift • Kotlin • MySQL • MongoDB

MY VALUES

Act with Integrity
Bias for Action
Make a positive difference
Empathy and Respect
Be Curious and Keep Learning

EDUCATION

OREGON STATE UNIVERSITY

MS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE June 2012 | Corvallis, OR

ANNA UNIVERSITY

BS IN ELECTRICAL & ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

April 2008 | Chennai, India

FIND ME ONLINE

Github: vasanthk

LinkedIn: vasanthkrishnamoorthy

Twitter: @vasanth_k Medium: @vasa Speaker Deck: vasa npm: vasanthk

EXPERIENCE

WALMARTLABS | SUNNYVALE, CA | MAY 2016 - PRESENT

Sr. Engineering Manager (Transactions) | Feb 2020 - Present

- Building a super app that unifies walmart.com and grocery into one app.
- Scaled up 4 teams, 3 managers and 36 engineers across Front End and Back End
- Scaled Checkout application to take in record # of orders during Holidays '20
- Drove a culture of operational excellence. Met SLAs and set up guardrails
- Led key GMV drivers: Walmart+, Guest Checkout, Promotions, Save for Later
- Stack: React, TypeScript, GraphQL, React Query, Tachyons, Jest, RTL, Next.js

Engineering Manager (Web Platform) | Sep 2017 - Feb 2020

- Founded & led Web Platform team of 8 engineers supporting 60+ devs/8 teams
- Improved site speed of walmart.com by 42%, contributing to XX million GMV lift
- Led several dev productivity & platform improvements setting up CI/CD, Mono-repo migration, Storybook integration, perf checks, bots & upgrades.

Staff Software Engineer (Cart & Checkout) | Apr 2017 - Sep 2017

- Led redesign of Payments and Checkout which improved conversion by 10%. We made it simpler (lesser steps to checkout) and performant (15% faster load)
- Tech led all React Native projects. Increased stability from 98.2% to 99.9%

Sr. Front End Engineer (Lead) | May 2016 - Apr 2017

- Rebuilt samsclub.com using React and components reused by walmart.com
- Shared React patterns and learnings from this project on Github (11k+ stars)

GOTOMEETING (Acq. By LogMeIn) | FRONT END ENGINEER (UI LEAD) Sep 2014 - May 2016 | San Francisco, CA

• Led Web portal projects for better user onboarding, meeting spaces, breakout rooms, meeting scheduler, ads, emails and developer tool integrations.

GRAPHIQ (Acq. BY AMAZON) | FULL STACK DEVELOPER (UI/UX)

Aug 2012 - Aug 2014 | Santa Barbara, CA

- Redesigned home page, nav and product page to reduce bounce rate by 22%.
- Built recommendation engine, content carousels, widgets, social features and a smart rating system that helps compare different products.

OREGON STATE UNIVERSITY | WEBMASTER

Sep 2010 - Jun 2012 | Corvallis, OR

• Migrated CS department website to Drupal and built new features such as student/company registration and reports to support job fairs/other events.

INFOSYS | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul 2008 – Aug 2010 | Chennai, India | Client: Lexis Nexis, Dayton, Ohio

• Boosted SEO traffic to LexisNexis by 90%. Accomplished this by transforming 40 million+ XML pages into SEO friendly HTML using XSLT, Java & PL/SQL.

TALKS

PerfMatters Conf '20: Turbocharging Walmart.com (Youtube) • Engineering Yourself in the Software World (Youtube) • What's new in React 16 • Building Multitenant UI with React.js • Taming the Asynchronous Beast in JavaScript • Web Browsers - Under the hood • What's the deal with React? • PerfMatters Panel AMA (Youtube)

PUBLICATIONS

"Building a Platform Team - Laying the Foundations" on Walmart Tech Blog